Yukigaoka
Kitagawa First
(日向翔陽･ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ)
＜中学最初で最後の公式戦
My first and last official match of junior high.
俺のチムは惨敗した＞
My team was creamed.
＜相手はコト上の王様＞
Our opponent was the King of the Court.
＜その王様に
必ずリベンジする
I swear I'll challenge him to a revenge match!
そう心に決めて
俺はこの烏野高校に進んだ
I made up my mind, and proceeded to Karasuno High School.
のに＞
However...
Wh...
なんでいる
Why are you here?!
Episode Two:
Karasuno High School Volleyball Team
≪なんで
なんでこいつが烏野に
Why?
Why is this guy at Karasuno?
≪いやでも人違いてことも
No, maybe it's someone else?
(影山飛雄)
((一体何しにここに来たんだ
What did you come here for?
((口で言うほど
簡単なことじゃねぇよ
It isn't as easy as it sounds!
((勝てコトに立つのは俺だ
I'll be the one still standing on the court at the end!
What have you been doing for the last three years?!
((お前は３年間何やてたんだ
No, there's no doubt! It's him!
≪いやいやこいつは間違いなく
影山飛雄
Kageyama Tobio!
お前去年の名前は知らない
You're that guy from last year.
Whatever your name is.
え
お俺の名前は日向翔陽だ
M-My name is Hinata Shouyou.
１回戦で
負かしたチムのことなんか
I doubt you would even remember a team you beat in the first round!
覚えてないかもしんないけどな
お前のことはよく覚えてる
I remember you very well.
≪ずばぬけた
反射バネスピドを持てた≫
This guy has outstanding reflexes, jumping ability, and speed.
≪にもかかわらず
能力を全然生かせていない
But he doesn't take advantage of these abilities at all.
やんにょやんのか
What? You wanna fight?
クソ下手くそなヤツ
You klutzy piece of shit!
ババカにすんなよ
D-Don't you make fun of me!
確かに
あのときはボロ負けしたけど
I know I got clobbered in that match,
次は負けない
but I won't lose next time!
あていうふうに
That's what I came here prepared to do,
so why are you here?!
固い決意して来たのに
なんでお前がいるんだ
同じチムにいたんじゃ
倒せないじゃねぇか
How can I kick your ass if we're on the same team?!
There are way more successful schools to choose from!
もとほかに
強豪て感じのとこがあるだろ
なんでそち行てないんだよ
Why didn't you go to one of those instead?!
県内一の強豪校には
I applied to the best school in the prefecture.
落ちた
But I didn't make it in.
You didn't make it?
コト上の王様なのに
く
But you're the King of the Court!
その呼び方やめろ
Don't...
call me that!
Huh?
Who knew that the setter from
Kitagawa First would choose us?
≪(澤村)いやまさか
北川第一のセｯタがうちにねぇ
≫(田中)でも
ぜてぇ生意気すよそいつ
But the guy is cocky. I just know it.
Not again. Would you stop trying to intimidate everyone you see?
(菅原)またお前だれかれ構わず
威嚇すんのやめろよ
I-I would never do such a thing.
(田中)
そそんなことしませんよ俺
ちわす
Hello!
おうおうおうおめぇら勝手に
Hey, hey, hey. What do you guys think—
(澤村)影山だな
おす
Are you Kageyama?
Hello.
(澤村)よく来たなぁ
(菅原)結構おきいね
Glad to see you!
He's pretty darned tall.
First impression are key, Suga!
最初が肝心すよスガさん
３年の威厳てやつを
ガと行たてください
Blast him with your upperclassman prestige!
ああ
(澤村)田中その顔やめろ
Tanaka, stop making faces.
Kageyama is slightly taller than them,
≪背は影山の方が少し高い≫
≪けどなんかでかいな高校生≫
but these high schoolers are still kind of huge.
That's right! I'm here, at Karasuno.
≪そうだ
俺烏野に来たんだよし
Okay...
Hello!
ちわす
(澤村)身長いくつだ
How tall are you?
180 cm.
１８０です
(田中)なんだと生意気な
Oh...
You're a cocky one, aren't you?
Hello!
ちわす
(田中)あああお前
え
Huh?
Hey, it's you!
The shorty who wore number one!
(田中)チビの１番
(菅原)ああ
Do you mean the other applicant named Hinata... is you?
(澤村)じゃあこの
もう一枚の入部届の｢日向｣て
お前か
え
I'm just a little surprised.
(澤村)いや
ちょとびくりしたなぁ
そうかお前らどちも烏野か
あの
I see.
So both of you chose Karasuno!
Um...
(菅原)俺たち
去年のお前らの試合見てたんだ
We saw you guys play last year.
(田中)
お前チビで下手くそだたけど
You're small and you were all over the place, but you had fight!
ﾅｲｽｶﾞｯﾂだたぞ
ああざす
Thank you!
(菅原)バネもすごかたよなぁ
You can jump pretty high too.
But you really haven't grown much at all.
(田中)それにしても
あんま育てねぇなぁ
うぐでも
I may be small, but I can jump!
小さくても俺はとべます
烏野のエスになてみせます
あ
I'll become the ace of Karasuno, you'll see!
(田中)おいおい
入て早々エス宣言か
Come on.
You only just got here and you're already claiming ace position?
いい度胸だな
う
You've got some balls!
What's wrong with having high aspirations? Right?
いいじゃん志は高い方がなあ
あ
が頑張ります
お前
I-I'll give it my best!
Now that you've announced that you're gonna be the ace, you better have improved.
エスになるなんて言うからには
ちゃんとうまくなてんだろうな
ちんたらしてたら
また３年間棒に振るぞ
Keep dragging your feet,
and you'll waste another three years.
なんだと
Excuse me?
(澤村)おおどうして
そういうこと言うんだ影山
Why do you say things like that, Kageyama?
俺だて精一杯
I did try my best...
Yukigaoka                  Kitagawa First
≪やたけど
I did.
でも今までの全部
ムダだたみたいに言うな
But don't make it sound like
everything I've done is for nothing!
(澤村)お前らさぁもう
敵同士じゃないて分かてる
Look, you guys. You do realize that you're not enemies anymore, right?
バレボルはつないでなんぼ
勝負しろよ俺と
Volleyball brings people together—
I want you to play me!
(田中)おい
大地さんの話の途中だろうが
Hey, Daichi is still talking to you!
Play you at what?
なんの勝負だ
バレの決まてんだろ
At volleyball! Duh!
How do you propose we play volleyball one-on-one?
１対１でどうやて勝負するんだ
えパパスとか
Doing passes and stuff.
パスに勝ち負けがあんのか
く
How do you win or lose at passing?
Listen, damn it!
聞けやこら
≫(教頭)騒がしいなバレ部
You're getting noisy, volleyball team!
(田中)げ教頭
(菅原)｢先生｣
Ugh! The veep!
Principal!
(田中)先生
(教頭)ケンカじゃないだろうね
Vice Principal!
You're not quarreling, I trust?
Not at all! This is what they call friendly rivalry. Right, guys?
(澤村)まさか
切磋琢磨てやつですよな
(田中)何かつうと
問題行動にしたがる教頭だから
We gotta behave ourselves,
'cause the veep wants us to misbehave.
おとなしく
サブ打てよ全部取てやる
Serve me the ball! I'll receive whatever you hit!
Hey!
(田中)こら
お前のサブ
I only received one serve from you last year.
去年は
１本しか取れなかたからな
With my face.
≪その１本も顔面だけど
俺だていろんな人たちと
練習してきたんだ
I've been practicing with all kinds of people!
もう去年までの俺とは違う
I'm not the same guy I was last year!
Not the same as last year, huh?
去年とは違うか
俺だて去年とは違うぞ
I'm not the same guy I was last year either.
(澤村)こらこら君たち
勝手なことはやめなさいね
Now, now, you guys.
Enough freewheeling.
(教頭)あれは１年生かね
Are those first-years?
≪落ち着けビビるな≫
Chill out. Don't let him faze you.
I've trained like crazy with the old ladies' serves!
≪おばちゃんたちのサブで
さんざん練習してきたんだから≫
行くぞ
Here goes.
A jump serve?!
≪ジャンプサブ
去年は普通の
He only did normal ones last year!
ううぐ
うわ
ひぇ
I dunno if I could get that one either.
≪ここんなサブ打つヤツ
No girls' or old ladies' teams serve like this.
女子にもおばちゃんにも
いねぇんだよ≫
それのどこが去年と違うんだ
How is that not the same as last year?
もう一本
おいいいかげんにしろ
One more.
Hey, knock that off.
(教頭)主将の指示を
聞かないなんて問題だねぇ
It's a problem that they won't take orders from their team captain.
≪反応速いきちり
正面でボルを捕らえ
Fast reflexes!
He's facing the ball straight-on, ready to—
ぶ
こんなことじゃぶ
If this continues—
あれヅラだたのか
気付くの遅ぇよ
That was a toupée?
You didn't notice?
We all noticed it during the entrance ceremony.
みんな入学式で気付いてたぞ
(田中)ぷぷお前ら
You guys! Shut up!
はははは黙れ
(菅原)田中も黙れ
You shut up, Tanaka!
(教頭)澤村君ちょといいかな
Sawamura, can I have a moment?
(澤村)
幸いにも特にお咎めなし
Fortunately, we have the benefit of the doubt.
謝罪もいらない
(一同)ほ
No apologies necessary.
But I want you to pretend you saw nothing.
(澤村)
が何も見なかたことにしろ
(澤村)だがお前ら
お前がちゃんと取らないからだ
You two, however...
It's your fault for not receiving it properly, you klutz.
下手くそ
何が｢去年とは違う｣だ
"Not the same as last year"?
Don't make me laugh.
ふざけんな
期待して損したクソが
You're such a let-down. You suck!
You talk too much.
いちいちひと言余計だな
(澤村)なあ
Hey.
少し聞いてほしいんだけどさ
I'd like you to listen to me.
お前らがどういう動機で
烏野に来たかは知らない
I don't know what motivated you to come to Karasuno.
けど
当然勝つ気で来てるんだろ
But you came here to win, didn't you?
はい
もちろんです
Yes!
Of course.
Karasuno's team could compete with the best up until a few years ago.
(澤村)烏野は数年前まで県内では
トプを争えるチムだた
一度だけだが全国へも行た
It happened only once, but they went to nationals.
But now, we're only in the top eight in the prefecture.
でも今はよくて県ベスト８
特別弱くも強くもない
We are neither weak nor strong.
他校からの呼び名は落ちた強豪
Other schools call us the fallen champs.
飛べない烏
The clipped crows.
烏野が｢春高｣で
全国大会に出たときのことは
I remember well when Karasuno competed in the spring national tournament.
よく覚えている
近所の高校のたまに
そこらですれ違う高校生が
I'd sometimes walk right past students from the nearby Karasuno High School
東京のでかい体育館で
全国の猛者たちと戦ている
who were competing against the country's best teams in a huge gymnasium in Tokyo.
鳥肌が立たよ
あ
It gave me goosebumps.
(([ﾃﾚﾋﾞ](観客たち)わあ
もう一度あそこへ行く
We're going there one more time!
≪小さな巨人と
同じコトに行く
We're going to the same court as the Little Giant!
全国出場を
とりあえずの夢として
There are plenty
of high schools that treat going to nationals like a tentative dream.
掲げてる高校なんて
いくらでもありますよ
(田中)バこの野郎
(澤村)心配しなくても
You bas—I mean, you...
There's no need to worry.
ちゃんと本気だよ
う
I'm serious about going.
(澤村)そのためにはチム一丸と
ならなきゃいけないし
We need a united team to accomplish that.
教頭にも
目をつけられたくないわけだよ
And that's also why we don't want the Vice Principal's watching our every move.
俺はさお前らに
Look, it isn't as though I'm telling you to be friends.
お友達になれて
言てんじゃないのね
中学のときにネトを挟んだ
敵同士だたとしても
In junior high, you may've been adversaries separated by a net,
今はネトの
but I want you go get it into your heads that
you'll both be on the same side of the net now.
こち側同士だてことを
自覚しなさいて
言てんのね
う
Is that understood?
(澤村)どんなに優秀だろうが
I don't care how good you are.
一生懸命でやる気があろうが
Or how hard you intend to play.
仲間割れした挙句チムに
迷惑をかけるようなヤツは
Anyone who causes trouble for the team with petty rivalry...
(２人)う
(澤村)いらない
is out!
互いが
チムメイトだて自覚するまで
I will not allow you to participate in practice
until you can demonstrate some team awareness!
部活には一切参加させない
ガシャン
(２人)はあ
Haikyuu !!
What?!
な
チムメイトの自覚て何
What's team awareness?!
どうやんの
知るか
How is it done?!
How should I know?!
P-Please let me in! Please let me play volleyball!
い入れてください
バレやらせてください
俺影山ともちゃんと
I'll get along with Kageyama, I swear!
≫仲よくしますから
お願いします
Please!
You sure about this, Daichi?
いいのかよ大地貴重な部員だろ
We need more members.
ていうかチムとかて
徐々になていくもんだろ
Besides, only time can make a team.
分かてるが
≫おいちょとどけ
I know that! However...
Hey! Outta the way!
ぐわ
すみませんでした
I'm sorry for my behavior!
I'll play alongside him!
こいつともちゃんと協力します
Please let me be on the team!
部活に参加させてください
ひ
Be honest.
試合で今のこいつと
協力するぐらいなら
If I'm stuck working with him in a match,
レシブも
スパイクもトスも全部
I'd rather do every receive, spike, and set by myself.
俺一人でやれればいいのにて
思てます
What the hell is with you?!
何言てんのお前
はははは
Why are you actually being honest with me?
I'm good with that kind of thing.
いいと思うよそういうの
でもさ
Still,
in volleyball, you can't drop, carry, or touch the ball twice in a row.
ボルを落としちゃダメ
持てもダメ
一人が続けて２度触るのもダメ
ていうバレボルで
How do you plan to play alone?
どうやて一人で戦うの
ふふ
ガシャン
お前なんなの実はバカなの
What's your damage?
Are you actually retarded or something?
(澤村)ライト
Right!
(澤村)田中
ブロクフォロちゃんと入れ
Tanaka, follow up when you block!
Yes, sir!
There's a court and a ball within reach.
目の前に
コトもボルもあるのに
I hate being in the doghouse.
お預けはひどいよ
くそ
Dammit! There's no time for this!
こんなことしてる時間はない
ささと入れてもらう
I'm gonna get inside!
チムメイトの自覚できたのか
Did you find your team awareness?
俺は戦力になる
I'm a force to be reckoned with!
That's reason enough to let me join their team!
部に入る理由なんて
それだけで十分だ
Spoken like a true king—
さすが王さ
ででもどうすんだよ
Anyway, what're you going to do?
We'll challenge them to a two-on-two match.
俺たち二人で
２対２の勝負を挑んで
If we win, we get to join.
勝たら入れてもらう
If we work together, we'll look like teammates, like it or not.
一緒に戦えば
嫌でも仲間ぽく見えるだろ
That will speed things up.
手とり早い
せ先輩相手にかよ
Against the upperclassmen, you mean?
What if we lose?
負けたらどうすんだ
負けねぇよ俺がいる
We can't lose.
I'll make sure of that.
What? Is this guy serious?
≪ええマジかこいつ≫
≪素か素で言てんのか
Is this normal for him?
I want you to give your absolute best effort
お前はできるかぎり全力で
to make sure you don't drag me down.
俺の足を引張らない努力をしろ
はあそんなこと言われて
'Scuze me?!
No one would agree to that after being talked down to like that!
｢はい努力します｣なんて言うヤツ
いねぇんだよ
じゃあどうすんだ
So what do you suggest?
ずと
そこから眺めてるつもりか
Do you plan to keep watching from outside?
中学で俺の出た試合は
The only match I ever played in junior high was the one against your team.
お前んとことのあの１回きりだ
We never had enough players to apply to tournaments until then.
それまで人足んなくて
大会に申し込みもできなかたし
And I had no place to play, so I always practiced in a corner of the gym or the hallway.
場所もないから
体育館でも廊下でも
いつも隅こで練習してた
≪廊下
Hallway?
So when I stood in the middle of that huge gymnasium for my very first match ever,
だから初めての試合
でかい体育館の
あのコトの真ん中に立たとき
自分が主役になたみたいで
it was like I had become the main character.
It was like, "whoa."
ぐわああてなた
≪ぐわああ
"Whoa"?
I wanted to stay there forever.
ずとそこにいたかたけど
コトに残るのは
But only the strong...
Kitagawa First
Loses Just Barely
強いヤツだけだからな
get to stay on the court.
どうすんだたぶん
二人で行かなきゃ門前払いだぞ
So what's the plan?
You'll be turned away unless we go together.
バレボルやれるなら
If it means I can play volleyball,
ちょとくらい嫌なことだて
俺は我慢できる
I can endure anything for a little while!
お前が
どんだけやなヤツでも極力
I'll do my best not to look at you.
That way I can't see what a bastard you are!
視界に入れないように頑張る
こちのセリフだバカ野郎
You took the words right out of my mouth, you moron!
Excuse me.
(清水)そこ通してくれる
Can I please get through?
(２人)あ
(田中)潔子さん
お疲れさまですお持ちします
Kiyoko! Thanks for all your hard work!
I'll carry that!
(清水)
いい自分で持ていくから
No, thanks. I'll carry it myself.
Kiyoko, you look lovely today.
(田中)
潔子さん今日も美しいす
ガン無視興奮するす
I love it when she ignores me!
うう
ガシャン
う
え
(部員たち)お疲れした
Good job!
(田中)｢勝負して
勝たら入れてください｣
Do you think they'll show up asking to be let join the team if they can beat us in a match?
とか言てきそうじゃないすか
あいつら
(菅原)ありえる頭冷やして
Probably!
All they have to do is cool their heads and demonstrate how they've learned the error of their ways.
ちょこと反省の色でも
見せればいいだけなんだけどなぁ
≫(日向･影山)キャプテン
(田中)な
Captain!
We would like to challenge you!
(２人)勝負させてください
俺たち対先輩たちとで
Us versus you upperclassmen!
(田中)わははマジでか
(日向･影山)せの
For real?
Three, two...
We'll prove that we can play together!
ちゃんと
協力して戦えるて証明します
I heard a countdown.
(菅原)｢せの｣て
聞こえたんだけど
I kinda like guys like them.
(田中)でも俺こういうヤツら
嫌いじゃないすよ
(澤村)負けたら
う
And if you lose?
どんなペナルティでも受けます
We'll accept the penalty of your choice.
Hm...
Club Application
ちょうどいいや
お前らのほかに２人
This should work.
Two other first-years are going to be joining us.
１年が入る予定なんだ
We'll have you play them, three-on-three.
そいつらと
３対３で試合やてもらおうか
毎年新入部員が入てすぐ
It's a match we hold every year for our new members to see what they're like.
雰囲気見るために
やてるゲムだ
But three-on-three?
でも３対３ですか
俺たち側のもう一人は
Who will be playing on our side?
Tanaka, I want you to be on their side on game day.
(澤村)田中お前当日
日向たちの方に入てくれ
(田中)え俺すか
(澤村)嫌いじゃないて言たろ
What? Me?
You said you kinda liked them.
I don't want to get dragged into their mess!
(田中)
関わるのはめんどくさいです
That's a shame. I really thought you were the only one capable of wrangling these delinquents.
(澤村)
そか問題児を牛耳れるのは
田中くらいだと思たんだけどな
(田中)んん
If you insist!
しょうがねぇなやてやるよ
I'll do it.
あ
(田中)うれしいかおい
Happy to hear that?
(澤村)
でお前らが負けたときだけど
So, in the event that you lose,
for the remainder of my time at this school,
少なくとも俺たち３年がいる間
Kageyama will not be allowed to play setter.
影山にセタはやらせない
Huh?
はあ
それだけですか
Is that all?
個人技で勝負挑んで負ける
自己中なヤツがセタじゃ
A team can't win with a grandstanding, over-aggressive, egocentric setter.
チムが勝てないからな
く
(澤村)どうした
What's the matter?
I'm not saying that your application will be rejected.
別に入部を認めないて
言てるわけじゃない
お前ならほかのポジションだて
余裕だろ
I'm sure you can easily handle other positions.
I'm a setter!
俺はセタです
勝てばいいだろ
Then win.
自分一人の力で勝てると思たから
来たんだろ
You're here because you thought you could win without any help, right?
What about me? I'm here too!
え俺は俺もいます
ゲムは土曜の午前
The match is Saturday morning!
俺も俺もいますよ
I'm here too, you know!
Listen up! Your upperclassman Tanaka here is gonna train the heck—
(田中)おめぇら
この田中先輩がビシと
Got it?
(澤村)いいな
ガシャン
(菅原)なんかさぁ
あいつらにきついんじゃね
Y'know... aren't you being a little hard on them?
You are being more strict than usual, Daichi.
(田中)確かに
いつもより厳しいすね大地さん
(菅原)
なんか特別な理由でもあんの
Is there a special reason for that?
くそ
なんだよ
Dammit!
What? Are you upset because you're the only one who gets penalized?
自分ばかペナルティあるから
怒てんのか
Well, even if you're not a setter, I'm sure you could get a starting position and begin playing just like that.
でもお前
別にセタじゃなくたて
すぐレギュラ取て
活躍できるんじゃねぇの
Besides...
それにセタより
スパイカの方がカｯコいいじゃん
spikers are way cooler than setters!
バシンつて
They get to slam the ball.
You bastard!
てめぇ
The setter is the team's playmaker!
セタはチムの司令塔だぞ
The setter is the one who has
the most contact with the ball!
試合中いちばん多く
ボルに触れるのがセｯタだぞ
支配者ぽくて
いちばんカコいいだろうが
It's the coolest position of all
because it makes you the ruler!
Huh?
え
てめぇの好きなスパイクだて
You can't hit your precious spikes
without a setter to set you the ball!
セタのトスがなきゃ
打てねぇんだぞ
But a setter's job is way too difficult, and it doesn't stand out.
だだてセタて
難しいくせに地味ていうか
お前でかい試合
生で見たことあるか
Have you ever seen a huge tournament in person?
No.
テレビで映す角度じゃ
分かりづれぇけど
You can't tell it from the angle you see on TV,
but if you watch from the end of the court,
コトのエンド側から見んだよ
そうすと
you'll be able to see how fast the setter sets the ball.
セタの超速ぇトスが
よく分かるんだよ
It flies from one side of the court to the other!
コトの端から端まで
ギュンて
Then the ball passes right in front of the opponent's blockers,
敵のブロクの目の前を
ボルが過ぎて
and you think, "Hey! Can he seriously hit that?!"
おいそれほんとに打てんのか
て思うんだけど
トスの先には
スパイカが跳んでてよ
But there's a spiker ready to strike that ball.
And he smashes that sucker in!
打つんだよドカンつて
おおう
R-Right.
確かにスパイカはカコいい
けど
The spiker really is cool, but it's the setter
敵のブロクを欺いて
スパイカの前の壁を切り開く
who tricks the opponent into blocking and breaks the wall open for the spiker to get through!
難しくてカコよくて面白いのが
セタだ
The setter's job is difficult, cool, and awesome!
お前がセタやりたいのは
よく分かた
I understand that you want to be the setter.
((影山にセタはやらせない))
Kageyama will not be allowed to play setter.
くそ何なんだ
勝てばいいんだろ
Damn!
What's his problem?!
We just have to win.
お前先輩相手でも
自信満々だたじゃねぇか
You looked confident enough
when you went to challenge them.
He's right. Don't let them shake you.
≪そうだ動揺すんな≫
This guy won't be any help.
≪こいつは当てにできないけど
あの２年の人にトスを集めれば≫
I just need to set for that second-year guy.
Hey! We have to work on your shitty receiving by Saturday!
おい土曜までにお前の
クソレシブなんとかするぞ
Shitty? Anyway, we won't be able to use the gym.
クソままあ
体育館は使えないけどな
≪(田中)
んんんああああ
Oh, yes.
明日も朝練は７時からですよね
I guess we really gotta start
morning practice at 7 AM, right?
(菅原)え
そうだけどいきなりなんだよ
What? Well, yeah. What got into you?
Oh, nothing.
あいやきょ教頭のヅラは
Do you think the veep's toupée made it out alive?
無事だたんですかね
(澤村)おおいその話やめろ
Hey! No discussing that!
(２人)明日
Tomorrow.
At 5 AM!
朝５時
遅刻すんなよ
Don't be late.
おめぇだよ
That goes for you.
≫ああちょ
カバンカバン忘れた
My bag! I forgot my bag!
Just what I was afraid of.
予想はしてたけど
鍵締まてる
じゃあ入れる窓探す
It's locked.
Okay, look for a window we can go through.
見つかたらやべぇだろうが
バカか
We'll get in trouble if we're spotted. Are you stupid?
Dang, 5 AM is a little tough.
(田中)
やぱきついなぁ５時は
Tanaka?!
田中さん
ふわぁ
７時前には切り上げろよ
Make sure to clear out by 7.
Tanaka!
田中さん
あざす
Thank you!
(田中)はははは
なんていい先輩なんだ俺
What a great upperclassman I am!
田中先輩と呼べ
(２人)田中先輩
You should show me some respect.
Yes, sir!
(田中)ははははもう一回
Again!
Yes, sir!
≫(日向･影山)田中先輩
≫(田中)わははは
Okay! Let's start practicing!
≫よし練習始めぞ
(田中)((確かにいつもより
厳しいすね大地さん))
You are being more strict than usual, Daichi.
(菅原)((なんか
特別な理由でもあんの
Is there a special reason for that?
((お前らも去年のあいつらの試合
見ただろ
You guys saw them play last year.
Kageyama supposedly had exception ability for a junior-high student,
影山は中学生としてはずばぬけた
実力を持ていたはずなのに
いまいち結果は残せていない
but he has almost nothing to
show for it. It needs to change.
そんであの個人主義じゃ
中学のリピトだ
His individualism will play out the same as in junior high.
チムの足を引張りかねない
He could drag down the team.
でも中学と違うのは
What sets the situation apart from junior high
今影山と同じチムに
日向がいる))
is that Hinata is playing on the same team.
Hinata? Well, yeah. He is kind of like a raw mass of agility.
(田中)((日向まあ確かに
運動神経の塊て感じですけど))
(澤村)
((うん実力はまだまだだけど
Yeah, but he isn't at his full potential.
He has extraordinary speed and reflexes, plus that jumping ability.
類いまれなスピドと反射神経を
持てて
加えてあのバネだ
But he didn't have a setter in junior high.
でも中学では
セタに恵まれなかた
Kageyama on the other hand wants a spiker fast enough to hit his sets.
そして影山は自分のトスを打てる
速いスパイカを求めてる
あいつら単独じゃ不完全だけど
才能を合わせたら
Apart, they're incomplete,
but put them together...
(澤村)
((コンビネションが使えたら
Get them to work in combination...
(澤村)
((烏野は爆発的に進化する
and Karasuno will evolve by leaps and bounds!
Don't you agree?
(澤村)((そう思わないか
ふざけんな俺が一番乗りだ
Screw you! I'm going in first!
Tanaka's already inside, so you can't be first!
もう田中さんが入てるから
一番じゃねぇだろ
そう思うならどけよ
If that's what you think, then move!
Hey! There's no time—
おい時間ない
うわ
We got a long way to go before combos come into play.
≪コンビネションとか以前の
問題だよこの野郎≫
Ooh, the gym!
うお体育館
(田中)昨日も来たろうが
You were here yesterday.
≪小さな巨人も
ここで練習したんだな≫
So the Little Giant practiced in here, huh?
≪よし
Okay!
≪やるぞ
Let's do this!
Next Episode Preview
Damn, thanks to Hinata, this is a horrific start.
くそ日向のせいで
さんざんなスタトだ
It's your fault for insisting on doing it all by yourself!
お前が全部一人でやりたいなんて
言うからだろ
I'd rather do it all myself than work with you!
お前とやるくらいなら
一人でやた方がマシだ
I'm telling you, that's the prob—
だからそれがダメなん
(田中)おい早起きしてまで
Hey, don't waste our early start on squabbling!
ケンカしてんじゃねぇ
(日向･影山)おす
Yessir!
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Episode Three:
A Formidable Ally
"A Formidable Ally."